gamingscan.com 2019-04-27

# Privacy Policy – GamingScan

## Who we are

Our website address is: https://www.gamingscan.com.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Usage data

Like millions of other websites, GamingScan.com uses Google Analytics to collect usage data on our site. We use it to track:

  * What website you came from to get here
  * Which pages that you visit
  * How long you stay on our pages
  * Information about your PC type and browser

Using this information, we get a better understanding of our visitors and which areas of our site that we should focus on. Occasionally, we compile aggregate statistics about the number of visitors that we get on our site – there is no personally identifying information being included in this type of reporting.

You can at any time opt-out of Google Analytics [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Push notifications

This website uses OneSignal, which is a notification provider. By opting in, you agree that we may collect anonymized data and send you browser notifications. You can always opt-out by following this guide: <https://documentation.onesignal.com/docs/opt-out-of-web-push>

The service is free to use for you and us, but in return, OneSignal Inc may sell anonymized data for research and advertising if you choose to opt in.

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

Furthermore, anonymized data may be sent to OneSignal Inc, which they sell for research and advertising, if you choose to opt in for browser notifications.

## Your contact information

When you contact us via our contact form or sign up through our giveaway or our newsletter, we will save your e-mail address and name if applicable.

##  **Amazon Associates Program and other advertising partners**

GamingScan.com is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to Amazon.com.

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include:

  * Google Adsense
  * Amazon Associates

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on gamingscan.com send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and/or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

GamingScan.com has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. GamingScan.com privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.

If you have any questions contact us [here](https://www.gamingscan.com/contact/).
